SHUBHAM GAUTAM

STUDENT

60, Gyan Vihar Ajmer (305004) 🔪 (+91) 99507-46862

⊠ sg2199203@gmail.com



ishubham21.github.io /Portfolio/

I'm an engineering undergrad and a programmer with hands-on practice on C and C++. I work as a Web Developer with experience in handling HTML, CSS and JavaScript coding, design and extensions to meet the organization's front-facing internet needs.

I'm also a content writer with a versatile style of writing and proficiency in researching, writing and editing diverse content.

EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2020

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

- Present

- Lead a team to develop a web-based ticket reservation system and thus, reduced the organization's reliance on third-party agents.
- Developing a Django-based restaurant utility system's front-end to make cafes more efficient by replacing conventional waiter-customer model.
- Contributed in developing a website for the college's technical club and helped enhance the UI of the website.
- Entitled as the highest performer in the software development section for the month of June, 2020 by Techknights.
- Developed a blog website to regularly post and update readers with my write-ups and content.

Nov. 2019 -Mar. 2020

EVENT ORGANIZER - STARTUP-GENIX

- Lead a team of 5 co-organizers and 15 volunteers.
- Managed to receive a sponsorship of INR 5Lakhs and mentorship support from iStart, Rajasthan for the event.
- Startup-Genix was a great success and was even featured twice by a local newspaper.

Oct. 2019 -Present

CREATIVE CONTENT WRITER - FREELANCE

- Gained 185K+ views on Quora in a span of 4
- Won 'Spin a Yarn', which was a literary event held at Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee.
- Collaborated with an Instagram blogger to write a series of letters under the name 'Will You?".
- Received a content-writing internship from 'Wise Kreator'.

SKILLS



CERTIFICATIONS

- IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator
- IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner
- Responsive Website Basics, University of London
- Introduction to CSS3, University of Michigan
- Introduction to HTML5, University of Michigan
- Udemy's Web Developer Boot camp

EDUCATION

2019-2023(exptd.)

RAJASTHAN TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, KOTA – B.TECH.

- Member (Website Developer and Maintainer) of Techknights (Programming Club of RTU).
- Organizer of Hackday@RTU, 2020 (Hacktoberfest).

2017-2019

MAYOOR SCHOOL, AJMER – CLASS 12TH

- Graduated with 92.4%.
- Received a 'Letter of Recommendation' from the Principal of Mayoor School, Ajmer.
- Member of Computer Club and MUN Club.

2013-2017

CHINAR SCHOOL, ALWAR – CLASS 10TH

- Graduated with 10 CGPA.
- Received 'Merit Certificate' from CBSE.
- Represented a model of 'Smart-City' at CBSE State Level Science Exhibition.

PROJECTS

- Community website (www.techknightsrtu.com)
- Django-based restaurant utility system
- Web-based ticket booking system
- Personal portfolio website
- Blog website
- Websites for real-time clients
- Website template for restaurants
- Tourist Portal using C++ (https://github.com/ishubham21/Tourist-Portal.git)

AWARDS & HONOURS

- Winner of 'Spin a yarn', a literary event held at IIT-Roorkee.
- Featured twice by a newspaper for my contribution in Startup-Genix.
- First runner-up in District (Ajmer) level science exhibition, inter-school English reading and 4*100mts swimming relay competition.
- 'Merit Certificate' from CBSE.'
- 'AEI Award of Excellence' by Ajmer Engineers' Institution.
- My project 'Smart-City' along with my name was featured by 'The Times', a national newspaper.

OTHER LINKS

- Github: github.com/ishubham21
- LinkedIn: linkedin.com/shubham-gautam-433019191
- StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.co m/users/13812772/shubh am-gautam